Evan Lin 林仰行

Taipei, Taiwan

+886 980 811 084 • yanghsin.lin@gmail.com • www.linkedin.com/in/proevan • github.com/proevan

Android App Developer

9 years Android app development experience in web browser, dating app, mobile event service and mobile advertisement industries. Dedicated to continually learning new programming languages, methodologies, and frameworks to deliver elegant, leading-edge applications, features, and functionality.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Diverse experience building apps and SDKs for business, personal users, including web browser, dating apps, event apps, instant messaging, social network, IoT/BLE apps, game guide apps, mobile advertisement SDKs for Android developers and official apps for department stores and movie theaters.

- Android App development 9 years
- Kotlin for production apps 5 years
- Android App Unit / UI testing 4 years
- App performance tuning 4 years

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

Kotlin, MVVM, MVP, Coroutines, Flow, RxJava, Dagger2, Room, Clean Architecture, Mockito, Espresso Scrum, Git Flow, Material Design, RESTful API, Unit Testing, UI Testing

Professional Experience

Senior Software Engineer, Mozilla — April 2019 - Oct 2020

- Refactored the code base with Kotlin, MVVM and Clean Architecture.
- Migrated the web browser engine interface using Firefox Android Component
- Built remote config friendly UI modules and helped the user growth by A/B testing
- Delivered the feature for FirefoxLite v2.0 and v2.5 with new home page, onboarding flow and verticals

Android Squad Leader, Grindr — Jan 2018 - April 2019

Serve as a squad leader in Beijing office to build new features and refactor the dating app which has 2 million DAU.

Key Achievement:

- Refactored the code base with Kotlin, RxJava, MVVM and Dagger2
- Improved the store ratings with 0.3 stars increased
- Helped to build the Taipei android team in Q3 2018

Senior Android Engineer, Etouches — Jan 2017 - Oct 2017

Serve as software developer for the event apps dedicated to adding the new features into existing apps including social network, instant messaging and lot/BLE interactions.

Cooperated with app team and QA team in Belgium and India.

...Continued...

Evan Lin 林仰行

Page Two

Key Achievements:

 Refactored and brought new Android app architectures(MVP, Dependency Injection), language(Kotlin), tools and Unit&UI testing into existing app products.

Senior Android Engineer, Loopd — Nov 2014 - Jan 2017

In independent role for the Android side, conceptualized, designed, developed, and implemented apps from the ground up using cutting-edge technologies and design.

Cooperated with product and sales team in US.

Key Achievement:

- Built stable, feature-rich apps for event customers.
- Designed and built beacon management apps for event operators.
- Used the latest technologies for Android development including Kotlin, MVP, Reactive programming, Unit&UI testing
- Made SDKs of Loopd Bluetooth devices

Software Developer, Waystorm — May 2012 - Oct 2014

<u>Technical Scope</u>: Android, Java, Windows Phone 7, C#, JSP, Struts, Hibernate, MySQL, RESTful API, JavaScript, Python, SDK Design, Proguard, MRAID, Admob, Google Analytics

Performed software development for one of the biggest localized mobile advertising network in Taiwan. And also contributed to several outsourcing projects.

Key Achievements:

- Rewrote and redesigned the advertisement Android SDK and client-server communication with new architecture independently.
- Made the SDK more stable, efficient and easy for developers to integrate.
- Implemented and maintained the official Android app for Breeze Department Store independently.
- Implemented and maintained the official front-end, back-end website and APIs for Breeze Department Store.
- Implemented and maintained the official Window Phone app for Vieshow Movie Theater independently.
- Generated a Taiwan district map in 2030x3500 2-dimensional matrix for LBS service usages which showing more than 300 districts using less than 1000 times Google Map API in 1 week independently

Side Projects - 2014 - present

Technical Scope: Android, Java, SWT, Jsoup, RESTful API, Parse, OpenShift

Built apps for outsourcing projects from different companies during off-work hours.

Key Achievements:

- Monster Strike Game Guide An official Android game guide app for Monster Strike
- SightsDoor A world travel guide Android app, which is an outsourcing project from a Japanese startup company
- Jeanz A customized sale alert Android app for jeans
- Paradise A private customized service which is able to sign in and crawl data from a particular website. And display the real-time data in an Android app, also send push notifications when events triggered.

Education and Training

Udacity — 2015 - 2016 Android Developer Nanodegree

National Taiwan University of Science and Technology — 2006 - 2010 **Bachelor of Computer Science**